Guide to the Oliver P. Merriman Scrapbook Collection, 1825-1942 CTC.1964.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Oliver P. Merriman Scrapbook Collection
1825-1942
1870-1942
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Merriman, Oliver P.
CTC.1964.01
14 Linear Feet (31 document boxes)
Oliver P. Merriman was an avid follower of Pittsburgh theatre. He built a large scrapbook collection that documents the history of the performing arts in Pittsburgh from the 1870s through the 1930s. It is organized into several broad categories and contains thousands of theatre programs, clippings, photographs, and other ephemera.
Scope and Content Notes
The Merriman Scrapbook Collection consists of 140 volumes of theatre programs, newspaper and magazine clippings, photographs, and other ephemera documenting Pittsburgh and New York performing arts history. For the most part, the materials date from before the 1870s through the early 1940s. About ninety percent of the contents of the collection relate to Pittsburgh theatre history and the remainder relating to New York City Broadway productions. Mr. Merriman had a very specific arrangement for the majority of the collection. Other than the scrapbooks being disbound and foldered, the collection has remained in that order. The materials are mounted in a series of nearly identical scrapbooks. With few exceptions, they measure 15 by 10 inches. The scrapbook's paper is still in good condition. The clippings from the 1930s and 1940s are brittle and have not held up as well as the earlier materials. The collection is arranged into seven series. The bulk of the collection is contained in the first two series: "Lettered" and "Numbered" scrapbooks. A selection of the original covers of the scrapbooks were kept and are stored in the last box of the collection.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh in 1964.
Biography
Oliver P. Merriman, 1866-1942, was a theater enthusiast who solicited materials and compiled a comprehensive and well organized collection of over 160 scrapbooks. The vast majority of these scrapbooks documented nearly a century of the performing arts in Pittsburgh. Mr. Merriman enjoyed a long career in the real estate department of Mellon Bank. He and his wife, the former Mary Louise Vogel, lived in the East End of the city and attended many of the productions documented in these scrapbooks. Merriman befriended theatre managers to help him collect programs for the performances that he could not attend and was also able to obtain programs from productions dating back to before the Civil War. "I collected them, but how and when and where I started I do not know. You know how you collect anything. You first throw it into a box. Bye and bye the box gets full and you realize that you are going to have to arrange the contents in some order." (Interview with Marie M'Swigan, Pittsburgh Press, January 12, 1930)
For about 20 years the Merriman scrapbooks were stored at the Allegheny Branch of the Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, until they were gifted to Dr. Ford E. Curtis in 1964.
Previous Citation
Oliver P. Merriman Scrapbook Collection, 1825-1942, CTC.1964.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The collection is organized into seven series.
Series I. Lettered Scrapbooks, 1870-1940
Series II. Numbered Scrapbooks, 1825-1942
Series III. Dated Scrapbooks, 1859-1942
Series IV. Coded Scrapbooks, 1866-1941
Series V. Scrapbook Stg. Stars - Stage and Its Stars, Past and Present, 1887
Series VI. Obituary Scrapbooks - "Final Curtain", 1894-1941
Series VII. Addenda Items List, 1880-1942
Performing arts -- New York (State) -- New York; Theater -- New York (State) -- New York; Performing arts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Theater -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Theater programs -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Theater programs; Merriman, Oliver P.
- Lettered Scrapbooks, 1870-1940; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series of Lettered scrapbooks make up the majority of the collection. Merriman centered his scrapbook collection around performers. Each letter of the alphabet has a series of scrapbooks. Most letters have a volume or more for actors and the same for actresses. There is also at least one volume for plays whose title begins with that letter. So, for example, scrapbooks A1, A2, and A3 are all contain programs, clippings, photos, and ephemera for actresses whose last name starts with A. A4 contains the same types of materials for actors and A5 for plays whose titles start with A. Within each scrapbook, the items are usually arranged in a chronological fashion, with the older plays, actors, or actresses appearing first. In some cases, there are autographs, correspondence, and other manuscript materials relating to the play or performer contained in the scrapbooks. In those instances, we have included a note here in the finding aid.
  - Scrapbook A1, 1876-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Mary Anderson, 1876-1940; 1876-1882; pages 1-31
    - Emma Abbott, 1878-1940; 1878-1890; pages 33-67
    - Marie Aimee, 1885-1912; pages 71-75
  - Scrapbook A2, 1885-1936 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Viola Allen, 1885-1923; pages 1-24
    - Margaret Anglin, 1899-1936; pages 25-45
    - Julia Arthur, 1923-1925; pages 47-49
    - Linda Abarbanell, 1912; pages 51-53
    - Lena Ashwell, 1906; page 55
    - Frances Alda, February 13, 1922; page 57
  - Scrapbook A3, 1881-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Maude Adams, 1881-1940; 1899-1936; pages 1-68
  - Scrapbook A4, 1871-1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Henri Appy, 1871; pages 1-2
    - Edwin Adams Fund, October 17, 1877; page 3
    - George H. Adams, 1881-1935; page 5
    - Louis Aldrich, 1881-1884; pages 7-9
    - George Arliss, 1912-1929; pages 11-17, 35
    - Maclyn Arbuckle, 1905-1933; pages 21-23
    - Edward Abeles, 1907; page 25
    - P. Aug. Anderson, 1919; page 27
    - George Ade, 1936; pages 29-33
    - Amos and Andy, 1931-1936; pages 36-41
  - Scrapbook A5 - (A) Plays, 1880-1942; 1894-1938 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Scrapbook B1, 1853-1940; 1881-1927 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - Caroline Richings Bernard, 1853-1876; pages 1-4
    - Anna Bishop, 1853; page 5
    - D. P. Bowers, 1874-1878; pages 7-25
    - Sarah Bernhardt, 1881-1940; pages 29-60
    - Fannie Louise Buckingham, 1881; page 67
    - Amelia Bingham, 1901-1927; pages 69-77
    - Black Patti, 1898-1900; page 79
    - Clara Bloodgood, 1904; page 81
    - Johnstone Bennett, 1891-1894; pages 83-87
    - Florence Bindley, 1904; pages 89-91
    - Eugene Blair, 1903; page 93
    - Nora Bayes, 1911-1937; pages 95-99
    - Alice Brady, 1920-1939; pages 101-103
  - Scrapbook B2, 1903-1941 (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
    - Blanche Bates, 1905-1941; pages 1-14
    - Billie Burke, 1903-1924; pages 15-27
    - Irene Bordoni, 1921-1926; pages 29-37
    - Mary Boland, 1932-1935; pages 39-44
    - Fay Bainter, 1920-1926; pages 45-54
    - Edith Barrett, 1931; pages 55-58
    - Joan Bennett, 1937; pages 59-62
      Scope and Contents
      Program for Stage Door at the Nixon Theatre is autographed by Joan Bennett.
    - Elizabeth Bergner, 1935; pages 63-65
    - Tallulah Bankhead, 1935-1941; pages 66-90
      Program for The Little Foxes at the Nixon Theatre is autographed by Tallulah Bankhead.
    - Vilma Banky, 1924; page 91
  - Scrapbook B3, 1865-1937; 1877-1920 (Box 2, Folder 8-12)
    - Dan Bryant, 1867; page 1
    - Blind Tom, 1865-1927; pages 3-5
    - Ole Bull, 1872-1873; pages 7-9
    - Dion Boucicault, 1877-1888; pages 11-19
    - Neil Burgess, 1879-1891; pages 21-23
    - Oliver Doud Byron, 1880-1894; pages 25-33
    - Signor Baldanza, 1882; page 35
    - William Barry, 1884-1932; pages 37-39
    - Digby Bell, 1891-1893; page 41
    - Pete Baker, 1888-1933; pages 43-45
    - Frederick Bryton, 1885; page 47
    - Harry Brown, 1886; page 44
    - P.F. Baker, 1883; page 51
    - Kyrle Bellew, 1902-1903; pages 53-57
    - Sam Bernard, 1903-1927; pages 59-67
    - Donald Brian, 1912; page 69
    - Wilson Barrett, 1887-1936; pages 71-76
    - Edmund Breese, 1910; page 77
    - Harold Bauer, 1920; page 79
    - Frank Bacon, 1918-1922; pages 81-89
    - Richard Bennett, 1913-1937; pages 91-93
    - Holbrook Blinn, 1925-1928; pages 95-103
    - Judith Anderson, page 98
  - Scrapbook B4, 1859-1939; 1878-1895 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - Edwin Booth, 1859-1939; 1878-1889; pages 1-63
    - Lawrence Barrett, 1878-1895; pages 67-92
  - Scrapbook B5, 1880-1940 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Boston Ideal Opera Company, 1880-1888; pages 1-10
    - Bostonians, 1895-1940; pages 13-52
  - Scrapbook B6, 1878-1942; 1902-1940 (Box 3, Folder 2-5)
    - Ethel Barrymore, 1902-1942; pages 1-25
    - John Barrymore, 1922-1926; pages 27-56
    - Lionel Barrymore, 1905-1925; pages 57-65
    - Three Barrymores: Ethel, John, Lionel, 1878-1942; 1920-1940; pages 67-99
  - Scrapbooks B7 and B8 - (B) Plays, 1877-1942; 1899-1938 (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
  - Scrapbook C1, 1879-1938; 1880-1928 (Box 3, Folder 10-12)
    - Jane Coombs, 1879-1881; pages 1-3
    - Kate Claxton, 1880-1924; pages 5-13
    - Ada Cavendish, 1880; page 15
    - Kate Castleton, 1883-1892; pages 17-21
    - Jennie Calef, page 23
    - Henrietta Chanfrau, 1909; page 25
    - Katharine Clemmons, 1893; page 27
    - Lottie Collins, 1893; pages 29-31, 41
    - Carmencita, 1891-1925; pages 33-40
    - Leslie Carter, 1889-1938; pages 41-64
    - Rose Coghlan Corrinne, 1878-1932; 1892-1932; pages 65-81
    - Henrietta Crosman, 1901-1913; pages 83-87
    - Emma Calve, 1897-1922; pages 89-94
  - Scrapbook C2, 1897-1940 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Annie Louise Cary, pages 1-4
    - Mrs. Patrick Campbell, 1902-1941; pages 5-18
    - Lina Cavalieri, 1913; page 19
    - Ina Claire, 1913-1938; pages 21-36
    - Ruth Chatterton, 1918-1939; pages 37-46
    - Constance Collier, 1932; pages 47-48
    - Marie Cahill, 1904-1939; pages 49-53
    - Cherry Sisters, 1897-1940; pages 55-60
    - Irene Castle, 1939; pages 61-64
    - Gladys Cooper, 1937; pages 65-68
    - Constance Cummings, 1937; pages 69-70
    - Ulric Cole, 1924; page 71
  - Scrapbook C3, 1917-1941 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Katherine Cornell, 1926-1941; pages 1-28, 51-60, 63-67, 73, 77-78
    - Jane Cowl, 1917-1936; pages 31-50, 61, 69-71, 75, 79-81
  - Scrapbook C4, 1876-1940; 1878-1928 (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
    - William H. Crane, 1876-1938; 1891-1928; pages 1-50
    - C.W. Couldock, 1884-1937; pages 51-58
    - Henry T. Chanfrau, 1877-1879; pages 59-67
    - F.S. Chanfrau, 1881-1882; pages 69-71
    - M.B. Curtis, 1881-1938; pages 69-71, 73-76
    - Bartley Campbell, 1878-1940; page 72, 79-125
    - John S. Clarke, 1878-1887; pages 125-129
    - W.F. Cody, 1882; page 129
  - Scrapbook C5, 1883-1941; 1900-1936 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - William Collier, 1883-1932; 1890-1909; pages 1-11
    - Richard Carle, 1907-1941; pages 13-19
    - James J. Corbett, 1892-1933; pages 21-25
    - Bob Cole, 1899-1900; page 27
    - Alexander Carr, 1920; page 29
    - Clark & McCullough, 1927-1936; pages 31-36
    - Walter Connolly, 1935-1940; pages 37-41
    - Charles Cherry, 1922; page 43
    - Will M. Cressy, 1909-1930; pages 45-47
    - Eddie Cantor, 1921-1939; pages 49-57
    - Joe Cook, 1928-1933; pages 59-66
    - Frank Craven, 1922-1938; pages 67-78
  - Scrapbook C6, 1884-1940; 1900-1940 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Cohans: George M., Jerry, Helen, and family, 1884-1940; 1900-1940; pages 1-79
  - Scrapbook C7, 1878-1938 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Colville, 1878-1880; pages 1-25
    - N.Y. Criterion Comedy Co., 1879-1886; pages 27-31
    - Carleton, 1879-1922; pages 33-39
    - Castle Square, 1900-1929; pages 41-45
    - Misc. Caruso, 1914-1921; pages 47-57
    - Chaliapin, 1923-1938; pages 59-67
  - Scrapbook C8 - (C) Plays, 1878-1942; 1900-1942 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Scrapbook D - (D) Plays, 1854-1939; 1884-1939 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook D1, 1877-1941; 1890-1940 (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
    - Eleanora Duse, 1924-1938; pages 3-13
    - Fanny Davenport, 1877-1941; 1877-1892; pages 15-58
    - Marie Dressler, 1890-1934; pages 59-70
    - Selina Dolaro, page 71
    - Helen Dauvray, 1886-1923; page 73
    - Dorothy Donnelly, 1928; pages 75-77
    - Camille D'Arville, 1895-1932; pages 79-81
    - Elsie de Wolfe, 1902-1934; pages 83-88
    - Hazel Dawn, 1914-1920; pages 89-92
    - Edith Day, 1924-1927; pages 93-95
    - Gaby Deslys, 1920-1940; pages 97-98
    - Dolly Sisters, 1918-1941; pages 99-102
    - Duncan Sisters, 1924-1936; pages 103-106
    - Ruth Draper, 1932-1935; pages 107-112
    - Fay Davis, 1904; page 113
    - Ray Dooley, 1927; page 115
    - Emma Dunn, 1917; pages 117-118
  - Scrapbook D2, 1878-1941; 1890-1941 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
    - Chas. L. Davis, 1878-1936; pages 1-22, 29-31
    - Alvin Theatre, 1940; pages 23-28
    - Frank Daniels, 1895-1935; pages 33-51
    - Robert Downing, 1897; pages 53-55
    - Henry E. Dixey, 1890-1906; pages 57-71
    - J.E. Dodson, 1909-1931; pages 73-75
    - Peter F. Dailey, 1893-1901; pages 77-79
    - Dan Daly, 1898-1900; pages 81-85
    - Jefferson DeAngelis, 1897-1938; pages 87-91
    - Donnelly and Girard, 1893-1941; pages 93-95
    - Lawrance D'Orsay, 1903-1938; pages 97-102
    - Leo Ditrichstein, 1906-1932; pages 103-105
    - De Reszke Brothers, 1888-1925; pages 107-111
    - Arthur Dunn, 1932-1938; page 113
    - Dante, 1940-1941; pages 115-118
    - Chas. H. Drew, 1880; page 119
  - Scrapbook D3, 1885-1938 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde, 1885-1930; page 1
    - Signor De Vivo, 1877; page 3
    - Duquesne Theatre, 1917; page 5, 19
    - Jack Dempsey, 1921-1935; pages 7-9
    - Eddie Dowling and Dudley Digges, 1921-1938; pages 10-16
    - E. L. Davenport, page 17
  - Scrapbook D4, 1892-1927 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Drew Family: Mr. and Mrs. John Drew, Mr. and Mrs. Sydney Drew, 1892-1927; pages 1-61
  - Scrapbook E1, 1878-1942; 1890-1940 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
    - John Essler, 1878-1887; pages 1-6
    - Wilie Edwins, 1882; page 7
    - Joseph K. Emmet, 1878-1889; pages 9-25
    - Evans and Hoey, 1885-1925; pages 27-29
    - Robert Edeson, 1899-1931; pages 31-37
    - Julian Eltinge, 1912-1941; pages 39-43
    - Leon Errol, 1925-1927; pages 45-52
    - Maurice Evans, 1930-1942; pages 53-93
    - Wallace Eddinger, 1922; page 95
    - Nelson Eddy, 1940; page 97
  - Scrapbook E2, 1879-1940; 1889-1928 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Effie Ellislee, 1879; page 1
    - Lizzie Evans, 1889-1940; pages 3-4
    - Katie Emmett, 1892-1927; pages 5-7
    - Maxine Elliot, 1892-1940; pages 9-17
    - Jeanne Eagels, 1925-1929; pages 19-26
    - Paula Edwardes, 1904; page 27
    - Emma Eames, 1904-1912; pages 29-31
    - Mary Eaton, 1928; pages 33-34
  - Scrapbook E2 - (E) Plays, 1878-1939; 1879-1937; pages 37-102 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook F1, 1864-1941; 1899-1938 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    - Mr. Chas. Fechter, 1864-1877; pages 1-7
    - Edwin Forrest, 1861-1932; pages 9-18
    - W.V. Florence, 1884-1889; pages 19-28
    - Eddie Foy, 1891-1941; 1900-1928; pages 29-49
    - Leopoldo Fregoli, 1896; page 51
    - William Faversham, 1899-1937; pages 53-72
    - Dustin Farnum, 1906-1929; pages 73-75
    - William Farnum, 1915; page 77
    - Douglas Fairbanks, 1924; page 78
    - W.C. Fields, 1925-1938; pages 79-84
  - Scrapbook F2, 1885-1938; 1896-1938 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Minnie Maddern Fiske, 1885-1932; 1892-1929; pages 1-36
    - Della Fox, 1896-1937; pages 37-45
    - Geraldine Farrar, 1919; pages 47-55
    - Pauline Frederick, 1928-1938; pages 57-60
    - Elsie Ferguson, 1914-1920; pages 61-64
  - Scrapbook F3 - (F) Plays, 1878-1939; 1883-1933 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Scrapbook G1, 1879-1941; 1898-1941 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - Maude Granger, 1879-1940; pages 1-4
    - Marie Gesistinger, 1883; pages 5-7
    - Ada Gray, 1887; page 9
    - Julia Gray, page 11
    - Grace George, 1902-1931; pages 13-21
    - Lulu Glaser, 1895-1911; pages 23-33
    - Mabelle Gilman, 1898-1903; pages 35-37
    - Kitty Gordon, 1912; page 39
    - Mary Garden, 1920-1923; pages 41-46
    - Adeline Genee, 1908-1910; pages 47-52
    - Helen Gahagan, 1898-1930; pages 53-55
    - Alma Gluck, 1921-1938; pages 57-59
    - Texas Guinan, page 61
    - Charlotte Greenwood, 1937; pages 63-64
    - Ruth Gordon, 1933; page 65
    - Lillian Gish, 1920-1941; pages 67-75
    - Dorothy Gish, 1929-1940; pages 77-84
    - Gladys George, 1934-1935; pages 85-87
  - Scrapbook G2 - (G) Plays, 1888-1939; 1912-1939 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Scrapbook G3, 1877-1940; 1890-1940 (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
    - Eliza Weatherby, 1878-1880; pages 1-5
    - Nat C. Goodwin, 1878-1919; pages 7-36
    - William Gillette, 1884-1937; 1900-1937; pages 39-71
    - J. Newton Gotthold, 1877-1888; pages 73-77
    - Richard Golden, 1891-1937; pages 79-87
    - Robert Gaylor, 1892-1935; pages 89-91
    - Robert E. Graham, page 93
    - Chas. A. Gardner, 1885-1924; pages 95
    - David Garrick, 1924-1933; pages 97-102
    - John Gilbert, 1888; pages 103-106
    - Horace Goldin, 1937-1939; pages 107-110
    - John Garfield, 1940; pages 111-112
    - John Gielgud, 1936-1940; pages 113-118
  - Scrapbook G4, 1932-1936 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - The Green Pastures, 1932-1936; pages 1-38
    - Souvenir Program of Gone With the Wind, page 39
  - Scrapbook H1, 1920-1940 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Walter Hampden, 1920-1936; pages 1-38
    - Walter Huston, 1925-1940; pages 41-63
    - Leslie Howard, 1929-1940; pages 67-78
  - Scrapbook H2, 1866-1940; 1890-1936 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
    - William Hayward, 1866; page 1
    - Hanlon Brothers, 1867-1902; pages 3-11
    - D. H. Harkins, 1877; pages 15-17
    - C. D. Hess, 1878-1883; pages 19-27
    - Chas. H. Hoyt, 1883-1940; 1883-1899; page 29, 31-58, 95
    - Wm. Hoey, 1889-1932; page 31, 55, 73
    - Edward Harrigan, 1890-1935; pages 59-61
    - Louis Harrison, 1884-1931; pages 63-65
    - Edmond Hayes, 1900-1906; pages 67-71
    - Gus Heege, 1893-1938; page 75
    - Hallen and Hart, 1889-1933; pages 77-81
    - Howard Hall, 1899-1920; pages 83-85
    - David Higgins, 1897-1936; page 87
    - John Hyam, 1912-1940; page 89
    - Taylor Holmes, 1920; page 91
    - Harry Hotto, 1866; page 93
  - Scrapbook H3, 1880-1941 (Box 8, Folder 5-7)
    - James A. Herne, 1881-1900; pages 1-12
    - E.M. and Joseph Holland, 1895-1926; pages 15-19
    - Raymond Hitchcock, 1910-1929; pages 21-29
    - Robert Hillard, 1895-1927; pages 31-33, 101
    - Charles Hawtrey, 1903-1904; page 35
    - Martin Harvey, 1920-1923; pages 37-39
    - Jos. E. Howard, 1910-1941; pages 41-42
    - Willie Howard, 1925-1932; pages 43-46
    - Glenn Hunter, 1925-1929; page 47, 107
    - Sessue Hayakawa, 1923-1926; page 49
    - Josef Hofmann, 1928-1937; pages 51-54
    - Anthony Hope, 1897; page 55
    - Edward Everett Horton, 1939; pages 57-60
    - James K. Hackett, 1898-1926; pages 63-77
    - Wm. Hodge, 1909-1927; pages 81-95
    - John Hare, 1880; page 97
    - Sir Cedric Hardwicke, 1936-1938; pages 99-106, 111-123
  - Scrapbook H4, 1892-1941 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
    - Victor Herbert, 1902-1938; pages 1-17
    - DeWolf Hopper, 1892-1941; pages 21-81
  - Scrapbook H5, 1878-1939 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
    - Pauline Hall, 1891-1892; pages 1-9
    - Anna Held, 1899-1918; pages 13-21
    - Maggie Harold, 1884-1887; pages 25-37
    - Lizzie Harold, 1880-1884; pages 39-41
    - Minnie Hauk, 1878-1929; pages 45-49
    - Agnes Huntington, 1891-1926; pages 51-53
    - Alice Harrison, 1885; pages 54-55
    - Julia Hurley, 1924-1927; pages 57-58
    - Louise Homer, 1923-1935; pages 59-61, 89
    - Frieda Hempel, 1919-1922; page 63, 91
    - Chrystal Herne, 1925-1926; pages 65-67
    - May Howard, 1894-1935; page 69
    - Virginia Harned, 1902-1904; pages 71-76
    - Katherine Hepburn, 1937-1939; pages 79-88
  - Scrapbook H6, 1921-1942 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Helen Hayes, 1921-1942; pages 1-126
  - Scrapbook H7, 1853-1941; 1880-1940 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Robert Heller, 1853-1915; pages 1-5
    - Herrmann, 1876-1938; pages 9-17
    - Houdini, 1925-1941; pages 21-32, 35-39, 42
    - Cardini, 1936; pages 33-34
    - Louis Krieger, 1940; page 41
    - John William Sargent, 1940; page 41
  - Scrapbook H8 - (H) Plays, 1878-1941 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook I, 1880-1940 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Henry Irving and Ellen Terry, 1880-1938; pages 1-29
    - May Irwin, 1898-1914; pages 31-33
    - Flo Irwin, 1898-1940; pages 35-40
    - Isabel Irving, 1903; page 41
    - Annie Irish, page 43
    - Irish Players (Abbey Theatre); Plays, 1884-1939
  - Scrapbook J, 1883-1941; 1889-1937 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
    - Emma Juch, 1889-1939; pages 1-11
    - Verona Jarbeau, 1888-1896; pages 13-19
    - Marie Jeritza, 1894-1934; pages 21-28, 41-46
    - Elsie Janis, 1906-1925; pages 29-40
    - Louis James, 1886-1899; pages 47-49
    - August Junkermann, 1893; page 51
    - George Jessel, 1927; pages 52-54
    - Carroll Johnson, 1936; page 55
    - (J) Plays, 1883-1941; pages 57-96
  - Scrapbook J2, 1874-1941; 1881-1936 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Joseph Jefferson, 1874-1941; 1881-1936; pages 1-40
  - Scrapbook K, 1873-1939; 1880-1938 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
    - Clara Louise Kellogg, 1873-1938; pages 1-7
    - Mr. and Mrs. Kendal, 1892-1900; pages 9-15
    - George S. Knight, 1879-1885; pages 17-19
    - Bertha Kalich, 1907-1939; pages 21-26
    - Annette Kellerman, 1915-1937; pages 27-31
    - Tessa Kosta, 1922; page 33
    - Doris Keane, 1914; pages 35-36
    - Madge Kennedy, 1923-1931; pages 37-50
    - (K) Plays, 1908-1939; pages 51-70
  - Scrapbook K2, 1833-1941; 1880-1940 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    - Edmund Kean, 1833-1939; pages 1-5
    - J. M. Kendig, 1869; page 7
    - Thos. W. Keene, 1881-1898; pages 17-25
    - Kellar, 1895-1922; pages 27-29
    - Ezra Kendall, 1904-1928; pages 31-33
    - Joseph H. Keane, 1886; page 35
    - John Kernell, 1892; page 37
    - John T. Kelly, 1922; page 39
    - Byron W. King, 1892-1940; page 41
    - Herbert Kelcey, 1898-1935; page 43
    - James Kirkwood, 1925; page 49
    - Kreisler, 1889-1940; pages 51-54
    - Dennis King, 1925-1934; pages 55-60
    - Gregory Kelly, 1927; page 61
    - Jacques Kruger, 1906; page 65
    - Jerome Kern, 1936; page 67
    - Effie Shannon, 1920-1941; pages 45-48
  - Scrapbook L1, 1870-1942; 1895-1940 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - J.Z. Little, 1883; page 1
    - Wilton Lackaye, 1895-1932; pages 3-15
    - Wright Lorimer, 1905-1920; pages 17-19
    - Robert Loraine, 1907-1913; pages 21-23
    - Harry Lacy, 1939; pages 25
    - J. Long, 1884; page 27
    - Jules Levy, 1887-1940; page 29
    - Al Leech, 1904; page 31
    - Bert Lytell, 1920-1930; pages 33-36
    - Harry Lauder, 1911-1927; pages 37-42
    - Fritz Lieber, 1929-1934; pages 43-50
    - Harry LeClair, 1882; page 51
    - Bert Lahr, 1939-1941; pages 53-56
    - Canada Lee, 1941-1942; pages 57-60
    - W.H. Leake, 1870; pages 61-63
  - Scrapbook L2, 1911-1930 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Lambs Club, 1911-1930; pages 1-26
  - Scrapbook L3 - (L) Plays, 1865-1942; 1890-1936 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Scrapbook L4, 1929-1940 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
    - Lunt-Fontanne, 1929-1940; pages 1-60
  - Scrapbook L5, 1867-1940; 1890-1938 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
    - F.W. Lander, 1867; page 1
    - Lotta Crabtree, 1880-1924; pages 3-19
    - Lillie Langtry, 1883-1940; pages 21-31
    - Francine Larrimore, 1926-1928; pages 31-34
    - Lucille LaVerne, 1924-1928; pages 35-36
    - Ada Lewis, 1925; pages 37-38
    - Mollie Lawman, 1888; page 39
    - Lisle Leigh, 1890; page 41
    - Cecilia Loftus, 1894-1940; pages 43-46
    - Eva LeGallienne, 1922-1938; pages 45-64
    - Gertrude Lawrence, 1937-1940; pages 65-74
    - Beatrice Lillie, 1928-1939; pages 75-82
    - Pauline Lord, 1922; pages 83-86
    - Margaret Lawrence, 1925; page 87
  - Scrapbook M, 1865-1941; 1878-1921 (Box 12, Folder 1, Folder 9)
    - Minstrels, 1865-1941; pages 1-166
  - Scrapbook M1, 1859-1940; 1880-1910 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
    - James E. Murdoch, 1859-1869; pages 1-3